# Daniel H. Tolbert

(404) 345-3008 - Daniel.tolbert4114@gmail.com

YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/user/danieltolbert4114

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-tolbert

## **Summary of Qualifications**

I am a young, experienced AV specialist with knowledge of AV software (mainly Adobe) through multiple class and personal projects as seen on my mentioned websites, hardware through studio, theater, radio, and conference experience, and system design. I have been around AV equipment and recording processes for eight years and am looking to grow as an Audio/Visual Engineer in any capacity of content creation. I am capable of learning different setups quickly and effectively. My strengths include high levels of energy, creativity, problem solving, responsiveness, and technological prowess.

#### Education

## **B.A. Film Studies and Production (3.61 GPA)**

Mercer University

May 2019

## **Applicable Industry Skills**

### System Setup/Installation

Knowledge of various hardware systems such as wireless microphone receivers, multi-input sound boards, large screen projectors, electrical controls, streaming/recording softwares (OBS and Adobe Creative Cloud specifically).

#### **AV Operation**

Worked conference center and radio soundboards where equalizing to different voice prints, managing live volume, and limiting feedback was necessary as well as in controlled spaces that required attention to detail that could muffle or distort recordings.

#### Videography/Photography

Experience with handheld DSLR cameras as well as studio dolly cameras. Able to rack focus quickly and effectively as well as find points of interest at live events and games. Managing active exposure levels with balance of aperture, shutter speed, and ISO as needed.

#### Lighting/Rigging

Off ground experience hanging units up to 20 feet in the air, patching them into circuits, assigning dimmers, cord management, limiting wattage and electrical load. Drafted paperwork including dimmer schedules and lighting plots as well as hung lighting plots for shows and performances.

## Work Experience

### Cox Media Group Athens: Part-Time Board Operator

June 2019 – Current

- Operated Live Audio/Radio feeds for various shows including UGA sports broadcasts, Bulldogs Live, Classic City Today, live remotes, and morning news/weather.
- Voice tracked, leveled, and edited the occasional traffic/news segment.
- Kept track of multiple schedules simultaneously while keeping time sensitive content on air and on time.

#### Mercer University: Student and Lab Assistant

August 2018 – May 2019

- Assisted with writing, photography, and editing labs to aid undergraduate students' work as well as ran AV responsibilities for the department.
- Worked in the ESPN3 Studios with studio sessions as both a producer and talent for student shows (Mercer Entertainment Review), opinion segments (WMUB Hot Takes), and other student projects.
- Trained in stage electrician work including lighting, rigging, patching, and creative design.

#### **Montreat Conference Center: Production Crew**

May 2018 – August 2018

- Tasked with live stage productions and sound design such as audio and visual troubleshooting as well as organizing wireless microphone use.
- Operated a 32-slider sound board as well as a stage lighting setup for live performances and keynotes.
- Worked in a small team where effective communication and workload distribution were key to keeping a high quality output.

#### **Groove Burgers: Bartender**

May 2016 – Current

- Tasked with serving and welcoming guests, general upkeep of the public areas, and communicating orders to the kitchen.
- Fiscal responsibility and kept accountable for all my transactions throughout the day.
- Personable and friendly towards the guests as well as actively engaged with the more extroverted guests.